Guide to the Charles A. Ferguson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles A. Ferguson papers
1943-1993
SC0475
Ferguson, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1921-1998
19 Linear feet
Correspondence, minutes, reports, proposals, surveys, research notes, articles, and other items pertaining to his research in linguistics; subjects include South Asian languages, East African languages, child phonology, and language universals. Also includes course outlines and final exams from classes he taught at Stanford; his autobiography; and minutes and papers from the Inter-Lutheran Commission on Worship, 1967-77.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of C.A. Ferguson, 1993-1996.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of linguistics at Stanford University since 1967. Prior to coming to Stanford, Ferguson was director of the Center for Applied Linguistics and taught and conducted research at the Harvard Center for Middle Eastern Studies and the Foreign Service Institute in Washington, DC.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, minutes, reports, proposals, surveys, research notes, articles, and other items pertaining to his research in linguistics; subjects include South Asian languages, East African languages, child phonology, and language universals. Also includes course outlines and final exams from classes he taught at Stanford; his autobiography; and minutes and papers from the Inter-Lutheran Commission on Worship, 1967-77.
Access Terms
Ferguson, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1921-1998; Inter-Lutheran Commission on Worship.; Stanford University. Department of Linguistics. Faculty.; Africa, Eastern--Languages.; Asia, Southeastern--Languages.; Language acquisition.; Linguistics--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Research, 1967-1988; Series 1
  Projects include Child Phonology Project, Language Universals, Phonology Archiving Project, and Language Survey of Ethiopia.
  - Stanford University Research in Linguistics and the Language Sciences-Statement of Purpose, March, 1967. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Child Phonology Project, NSF grant proposal, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Child Phonology Project, Dept. of H, E, & W grant proposal, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Child Phonology Project, article & bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Learning to Pronounce: Stanford Papers on Child Phonology, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Learning to Pronounce: Stanford Papers on Child Phonology, notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Learning to Pronounce: Stanford Papers on Child Phonology, correspondence (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Linguistic Minorities Project, correspondence & reports, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Working Conference on Language Database Archiving and Information Exchange, NEH grant proposal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Case studies in Language Development, proposals and budget (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aspects of the Acquisition of English and Spanish Phonology, NSF grant proposal, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Acquisition of Semantic Distinctions in Children’s Speech, NSF grant info. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tajiki notes (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Aspects of the Acquisition of English Phonology, NSF grant proposal, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Language Diversity and National Development, proposal, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Language Diversity and National Development: Characterization of Mbugu as a possible Cushitic-Bantu Creole, NSF grant proposal, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Research Project on Language Universals, proposal, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Language Universals Project, correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Language Universals Project: Computer Archive for Language Universals Project (CALM), NSF grant proposal, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Language Universals Project - Guidelines for Studying (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Language Universals Computer Archive: North Greenlandic - Vowel Rules (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Language Universals Computer Archive: North Greenlandic - Consonant Rules (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Language Universals Project: Some Generalizations Concerning Glottalic Consonants, J.H. Greenberg (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Language Universals Computer Archive: coding sheets (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Phonology Archiving Project (P.A.P.), proposal, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Phonology Archiving Project, proposal for renewal, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Phonology Archive Coding Manual (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Phonology Archiving Project, reports: Prelim. - 6 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Phonology Archiving Project, bibliography and list of research projects (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Phonology Archive questionnaire, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Phonology Archive printouts (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Language Universals Phonology Archive, checklists (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Phonology Archive Retrieval Invitation, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Language Universals Phonology Archive, coding manuals - early drafts (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Phonology Archive related articles (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Phonology Archive, general info, reports, correspondence (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Language Universals Project staff 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Phonology Archiving Project, NSF proposal for renewal, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Word Order Archive proposal (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Case Systems Archive proposal (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pronominal Systems Archive proposal (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Grammatical Category Archive proposal (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Survey of Language Use and Language Teaching in East Africa, proposals and background (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Survey of Language Use and Language Teaching in East Africa: Language Learning Patterns in Ethiopia as Reported by HSIU Freshmen in Degree Programs (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Survey of Language Use and Language Teaching in East Africa, budget info. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Survey of Language Use of Language Teaching in East Africa: Bulletin, May & August, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Survey of Language Use and Language Teaching in East Africa, Advisory Committee and Staff Committee meeting minutes, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Survey of Language Use and Language Teaching in East Africa, memos and correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia, Survey Monograph: Language in Ethiopia (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia: A Short Description of Tigrinna Grammar (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia: A Short Into to Gallinya (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia, misc. language notes (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - “Role of Arabic in Ethiopia”: paper by Ferguson with notes and articles (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ethiopian Language Conference - papers (October 30-November 1, 1969) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Linguists - Lists of Specialists in African Languages (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Survey on Language in Ethiopia, correspondence 1969-1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Language Association of East Africa, correspondence, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Language Association of East Africa (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Language in East Africa - reprints of various articles (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Ethiopian Language Area (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - African Languages - research proposals and scholarship applications (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Statistics on Villages in West Jordan (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia, working papers (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia, word lists, key, etc. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ethiopian Language Statistics (by province) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia, elicitation forms (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Language in Ethiopia, questionnaire drafts (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Language Study of Ethiopia (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Language Study of Ethiopia committee meeting minutes, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Directory of Ethiopian Language Specialists (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Classification of Ethiopian Languages (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Language Study of Ethiopia, correspondence & memos (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia - Arabic language questionnaire (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia - Arabic language questionnaire (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia - Arabic language questionnaire (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia - Arabic language questionnaire (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Language Survey of Ethiopia - Arabic language questionnaire (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Biographical files, 1946-1993; Series 2
  - C. A. Ferguson Autobiography (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - C. A. Ferguson Bibliography - 1945-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C. A. Ferguson Curriculum Vitae (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C. A. Ferguson Interview on Sociolinguistics - 03/93 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American - Scandinavian Association Fellowship Application 1946 by C. A. Ferguson (rejected) - Includes transcript (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Professional files, 1945-1991; Series 3
  Subjects include the American Committee on South Asian Languages, Foreign Service Institute, Center for Applied Linguistics, and the Dept. of Linguistics at Stanford.
  - Deccan College Programs (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee on South Asian Languages - Fellowship in India Applicants (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Committee on South Asian Languages - Deccan College Fellowship for study in U. S. Applicants (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Bordie, John) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Bright, William) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Brown, A. F. R.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Dimock, E. C.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Fairbanks, Gordon) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Gleason, Henry) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Kelley, Gerald) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Levine, Lewis) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Liskar, Leigh) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Southworth, Franklin) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Fellowship in India (Staneslow, Paul) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Project Correspondence, Jan - Mar 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Project Correspondence, Apr - July 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Committee on South Asian Languages Deccan College Project Correspondence, Aug - Dec 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Project Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - ACSAL Inter-University Summer Programs, 1958, 1959, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ACSAL Deccan College Seminars on Contemporary Writing in East Pakistan (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ACSAL travel records (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ACSAL bank records 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ACSAL bank records 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - ACSAL checking account ledger 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ACSAL checking account ledger 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - ACSAL reports, memos, minutes 1953 - 1959 (not in order) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American Committee on South Asian Languages, correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ACSAL, correspondence, Jan.-Apr. 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ACSAL, correspondence, May-Dec. 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ACSAL, general correspondence, 1956-58 and miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Proposal for Middle East Studies at Stanford, July 1988 & Nov 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Middle East Studies at Stanford, correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - American Association of Teachers of Arabic, Minutes from Nov. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Middle East - Miscellaneous Reprints (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Black English Features (reprint) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints of Articles (not by C.A.F.) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - “A Study of Verb Phrases Used by Five Year Old Nonstandard Negro English Speaking Children,” S. N. Henrie, Professional (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - “Non - Segmental Phonology in First - Language Acquisition,” D. Crystal (reprint) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Organic Alphabet (Iran) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - “Toward a Grammar of Syntactic Change,” Elizabeth Closs Traugott (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Foreign Language Pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - “Note Alla Grammatica,” M. M. Moreno (reprint) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - International Conference on Second Language Problems, news article, 22 April 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - International Conference on Second Language Problems, agendas of participants (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - International Conference on Second Language Problems, reports, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - International Conference on Second Language Problems, correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Conference on Sociolinguistic Oriented Language Surveys, agenda & notes (Sept 6-7, 1971) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Conference on Sociolinguistic Oriented Language Surveys, correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Phonological Development - Proposal 1988 (rejected) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Phonological Development - Proposal 1989 (accepted) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Child Phonology Conference, University of Wisconsin, 05/30-01/90 (agenda & notes) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Werner/Gren Conference (1970) - Toward the Description of the Languages of the World, general information & reports (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Werner/Gren Conference (1970) - Toward the Description of the Languages of the World, papers by participants (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Conference on the Languages of the World (1970), general information & reports (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - China Trip Notebook #1 - Linguistics Delegation to China, 1974 (correspondence & readings) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - China Trip Notebook #2 - Linguistics Delegation to China, 1974 (readings) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - China Trip Notebook #3 - Linguistics Delegation to China, 1974 (correspondence & memos) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Foreign Service Institute, Misc. notes on language (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - FSI, Dept. of State Memos (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - FSI, Misc. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - FSI, general correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - FSI, general correspondence 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - FSI, general correspondence, 1949-1956 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - FSI, Language Training Course A-140w “Intro to the USIE”; schedules, notes, materials (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - FSI, Language Training School, University Resources (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - FSI, Spanish training material (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - FSI, Info on Arabic (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - FSI, Info on Persian (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - FSI, resources in Beirut, Lebanon training center, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - FSI, Cairo correspondence 1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - FSI, C.A.F. trip to Beirut correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - American Friends Service Committee 1944-1946 (training in Finnish and Bengali) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: transition from Penn to FSI (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - FSI, Trip to Iran, travel (itineraries) info. and receipts, Sept. 1949-Jan. 1950 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - FSI, Trip to Iran 1949-1950; bio. of Ferguson (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - FSI, Trip to Iran, reports on side-trips 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - FSI, Trip to Iran 1949-1950, reports on language training centers (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - FSI, Trip to Iran 1949-1950, “Notes for American Visitors to Baghdad” (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - FSI, Trip to Iran 1949-1950, correspondence (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - FSI, Trip to Iran 1949-1950, Embassy language classes, info and flash cards (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - CAL (Center for Applied Linguistics), Development Committee, correspondence & memos 1977-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - CAL Development Committee meeting agendas and notes (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - CAL, Reports (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - CAL, “French-English Contrastive Phonology” draft (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - CAL, “French-English Contrastive Phonology” second draft (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - CAL, “French-English Contrastive Phonology” spectrograms (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - CAL, Study of English Teaching in India (1966), correspondence (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - CAL, Study of English Teaching in India (1966), final report with drafts (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - CAL, Study of English Teaching in India (1966), reports (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - CAL, 1983 CAL Books catalog (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - CAL, misc. correspondence and memos 1964-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - CAL, Language files: List of languages with numbers of native speakers, December 1969 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - CAL, “Ethiopia: A Profile of Languages and their Use.” 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Linguistics business correspondence 1968 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Linguistics business correspondence 1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Linguistics community, bilingualism project 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Linguistics community 1970 (re: campus protest movement) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Sociolinguistics by J.A. Fishman, intro by CAF (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Language Problems and Language Planning, editorial board (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Journal of Child Language, editorial board (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Language in Society, editorial board 1973-1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Language Associations questionnaires (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - ESL, English Language Teaching Materials catalog (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Misc. language - related newspaper articles (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography of American Indian Language Classification (professional) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Misc. (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Classes, 1973-1987; Series 4
  - Linguistics 206: Topics in Discourse Analysis: Genre (Spring 1985) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Linguistics 225: Archiving Workshop (Fall 1973) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Linguistics 276: Register, Genre, and Style (Summer 1987), reading materials (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Linguistics 360: Seminar in Developmental Psychology: Children’s Narrative (1979-1980), syllabus, notes, etc. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Religious activities, 1956-1987; Series 5
  Includes records from the Inter-Lutheran Task Force on Worship, the Sub-Committee on Prayer, and the Consultation on Common Texts, as well as Ferguson's writings on religious issues.
  - “An Advent Psalm”, C.A.F. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - “The Communion of Saints,” C.A.F. (final copy) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - “The Communion of Saints,” C.A.F. (final copy #2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - “The Communion of Saints,” C.A.F. (incomplete draft #1) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “The Communion of Saints,” C.A.F. (draft #2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - “The Communion of Saints,” C.A.F. notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - “The Communion of Saints,” correspondence, 1956-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - “Lutheran Airport Chapels” and “Traveler’s Prayer,” C.A.F. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ministry of Healing (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - “25 Saints,” C.A.F. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Consultation on Common Texts (CCT), meeting minutes and notes, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - CCT, Contemporary Adaptations of Psalms (by Psalm) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - CCT, misc. contemporary adaptations (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - CCT, Statement on the 20 adaptations of Psalms for contemporary worship, C.A.F. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CCT, “The Morning Sufferage in Contemporary English,” C.A.F. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CCT, Contemporary Adaptations of Psalms (sets of Psalms) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - CCT, Contemporary Liturgy pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CCT, Psalm studies, C.A.F. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Psalter Committee (CCT) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CCT Psalter Project correspondence and memos, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Inter-Lutheran Task Force on Occasional Services: Proposals for Review and Study, Sept. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Inter-Lutheran Task Force on Occasional Services: Proposals for Review and Study, December 1980 and March 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Inter-Lutheran Task Force on Occasional Services, minutes & memos (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Inter-Lutheran Task Force on Occasional Services, misc. notes (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Inter-Lutheran Commission on Worship, calendars and lectionary (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - ILCW - bibliography 1967, updated 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, prayers for lesser festivals (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, working drafts of prayers by C.A.F. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Contemporary collects (and related correspondence) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, misc. prayers and poems (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memos to Sub-committee on Prayer - Liturgical Text Committee action (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, correspondence, 1967-72 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, Prayers of the Roman Missal Project 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, first meeting March 5-7, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, February 8-10, 1973 meeting (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, “Prayers of the day and season” (collects) correspondence (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, “Prayers of the day and season” drafts #1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sub-committee on Prayer, “Prayers of the day and season” drafts #2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - ILCW Liturgical Texts Committee, “Propers for Holy Communion” (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - ILCW Liturgical Texts Committee, “Bases for CCA Concern for Inclusive Language” (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - “Paper on Ministry and Ordination - LC/USA” (L.T.C.) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - ILCW Liturgical Texts Committee, subcommittee reports, minutes, proposals (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - ILCW Liturgical Texts Committee, correspondence, memos, notes (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - ILCW Liturgical Texts Committee, misc. liturgical texts (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - ILCW Liturgical Texts Committee, misc. articles (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - LSWMA correspondence (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ILCW meeting minutes (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ILCW April 26-28, 1976 meeting exhibits (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ILCW Lutheran pamphlets (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ILCW Worship brief - newsletters, assorted issues 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Stance newsletter 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - LSWMA Lutheran Society for Worship, Music, and the Arts - bulletins 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - “Response: In Worship - Music - the Arts” (publication) 1968 and 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ILCW photographs 1975 & 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Memos to Standing Liturgical Commission, Nov. 1968 - June 1969 (including prayer drafts) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Memos to standing Liturgical Commission, August 1969 (including prayer drafts) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Work on calendar of lesser festivals (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Evening sufferages (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Statement on Anointing and Healing (LCA) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Misc. liturgies from University Lutheran Church (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1971 revision of Historic Western Pericopes for the Church Year (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Language and the Church survey, 1980 (Lutheran Church in Australia) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Language and the Church survey, 1980 (Lutheran Church in Australia), completed surveys #1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Language and the Church survey, 1980 (Lutheran Church in Australia), completed surveys #2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Evangelical Church in Austria (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ethiopian Evangelical Church (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - African Consultation on Christian Social Responsibility, November 14-21, 1968 (religious files) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Lutheran Church in the Philippines, “Shareletters” 1968-1969 and the Philippine Lutheran Newsletter 1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lutheran Church in the Philippines, liturgy (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Language Policy in Churches in New Guinea (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - “Saints and Linguists” work by C.A.F. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - “Guidelines for Avoiding Bias in Publications of the American Lutheran Church” (Box 6, Folder 11)